[{"id":1,"question":"何分待たないといけませんか？","answer":"How long do I have to wait?","tips":"How long // ~~do I~~ **have** ~~to~~ **wait**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":2,"question":"私が道案内できます","answer":"I can show you the way.","tips":"~~I can~~ **show** you **way**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":3,"question":"次の交差点を曲がってください","answer":"Turn at the next intersection.","tips":"**Turn** // ~~at the~~ next // inter*sec*tion","level":"Beginner"},{"id":4,"question":"それは通りを挟んで反対側の道沿いにあります","answer":"It's across the street on the other side.","tips":"~~It's~~ **a*cro*ss** the *stree*t // ~~on the~~ *o*ther *si*de","level":"Moderate"},{"id":5,"question":"明日博物館は休みかもしれませんね","answer":"The museum might be closed tomorrow.","tips":"~~The~~ mu*se*um // ~~might be~~ **closed** to*mo*rrow","level":"Beginner"},{"id":6,"question":"隣座ってもいいですか？","answer":"Would you mind if I sit next to you?","tips":"~~Would you mind if I~~ **sit** next ~~to~~ you(↗)","level":"Hard"},{"id":7,"question":"お連れの人はいますか？","answer":"Are you with anyone?","tips":"~~Are~~  you ~~with~~ *a*nyone(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":8,"question":"定休日はありますか？","answer":"Do you have any days you’re closed?\t","tips":"~~Do you~~ *ha*ve *a*ny *day*s ~~you’re~~ *clo*sed(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":9,"question":"一番上の棚のソーダを2本取ってもらえますか？","answer":"Can you give me two cans of soda water from the top shelf?","tips":"~~Can you~~ // *gi*ve me // **two** **cans** ~~of~~ *so*da *wa*ter // ~~from the~~ *to*p *she*lf(↗)","level":"Hard"},{"id":10,"question":"どれがおすすめですか？（レストランのメニューを見つつ）","answer":"Could you recommend something from the menu?","tips":"~~Could you~~ re*com*mend *some*thing // ~~from the~~ *men*u(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":11,"question":"私はパンよりお米の方が好きです.","answer":"I prefer rice over bread.","tips":"I **pre*fer*** // rice ~~over~~ bread","level":"Beginner"},{"id":12,"question":"彼は確か日本人と結婚してませんでしたっけ？","answer":"I thought he was married to a Japanese person, wasn't he?","tips":"I thought // ~~he was~~ *mar*ried // ~~to a~~ **Japa*nese*** *per*son(↘) // **wasn’t** he(↗)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":13,"question":"（コンドのレセプションで）水道料金の請求書は（私のメールボックスに）届いてますか？","answer":"Has the water bill been delivered to my mailbox yet?","tips":"~~Has the~~ *wa*ter **bill** been **de*li*vered** // ~~to my~~ *mail*box **yet**(↗)","level":"Hard"},{"id":14,"question":"計算間違えてますよ（レジの店員に対して）","answer":"I think there’s a mistake with the total.","tips":"I think ~~there’s a~~ *mis*take ~~with the~~ ***to*tal**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":15,"question":"12階を押してください（エレベーターでやや丁寧に）","answer":"Could you press the 12th floor, please?","tips":"~~Could you~~ *pre*ss ~~the~~ **12th** **floor**, please(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":16,"question":"うわぁ、また停電になったよ。シャワーすら浴びれないじゃん","answer":"Ugh, another power outage? I can’t even take a shower.","tips":"**Ugh**, a*no*ther *pow*er *out*age(↗) // I can’t ***e*ven** *ta*ke ~~a~~ *show*er","level":"Moderate"},{"id":17,"question":"この国の突然の停電にはうんざりしている。","answer":"I’m fed up with the sudden power outages in this country.","tips":"I’m *fe*d *u*p // ~~with the~~ *sud*den *pow*er *out*ages // ~~in this~~ *coun*try","level":"Hard"},{"id":18,"question":"インフラ技術がいい加減なんだよ","answer":"The infrastructure is really unreliable.","tips":"~~The~~ ***in*frastructure** // ~~is~~ *real*ly ***re*liable**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":19,"question":"せっかく散歩して時間つぶしてきたのに","answer":"I went for a walk to kill time, but it was all for nothing.","tips":"~~I~~ went ~~for a~~ *wal*k // ~~to~~ kill *ti*me // ***bu*t** ~~it was~~ **all** *fo*r *no*thing","level":"Hard"},{"id":20,"question":"こういう事が起こるとこの国に対するたくさんの不満で頭が一杯になる","answer":"Whenever things like this happen, my mind gets overwhelmed with all my frustrations with this country.","tips":"~~Whenever~~ things ~~like~~ this ***ha*ppen**(↘) // ~~my~~ mind gets over*whelmed* // ~~with all my~~ **frus*tra*tions** ~~with this~~ *coun*try","level":"Extreme"},{"id":21,"question":"今はまともに電気使えないから、また寝るわ。","answer":"I can’t even use electricity properly right now, so I’m just going back to sleep.","tips":"I **can’t** even use **elec*tri*city** // ***prop*erly** **right** now(↘) // so ~~I’m just~~ going back ~~to~~ **sleep**\n","level":"Extreme"},{"id":22,"question":"まあ、こういう時は気を取り直して散歩でも行きましょうか。","answer":"Well, let's shake it off and go for a walk.","tips":"~~Well~~ // **let’s** shake ~~it~~ off // ~~and~~ go ~~for~~ ~~a~~ walk","level":"Hard"},{"id":23,"question":"ベッドメイキングします。","answer":"I’ll make the bed.","tips":"I’ll make ~~the~~ **bed**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":24,"question":"インターネットを使わせてもらえますか？","answer":"Could I use the Wi-Fi, please?","tips":"~~Could I~~ use ~~the~~ ***Wi*-Fi**// ~~please~~(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":25,"question":"重そうなので、袋を二重にしてもらえますか？","answer":"Could you double-bag it? It looks heavy.","tips":"~~Could~~ you ***dou*ble**-*ba*g ~~it~~(↗) // It *looks ***hea*vy**(↘)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":26,"question":"現金以外だとどんな支払い方法がありますか？","answer":"What payment methods are available besides cash?","tips":"**What** *pay*ment *meth*ods // ~~are~~ **a*vai*lable** // be*si*des **cash**","level":"Hard"},{"id":27,"question":"今そっちに向かってます","answer":"I’m on my way now.","tips":"~~I’m on my~~ **way** now","level":"Beginner"},{"id":28,"question":"何人兄弟ですか？","answer":"How many siblings do you have?","tips":"**How** *ma*ny *sib*lings // ~~do~~ you **have**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":29,"question":"なんでセブに住んでるんですか？","answer":"What brought you to live in Cebu?","tips":"***Wha*t** *brough*t you ~~to~~ live ~~in~~ **Ce*bu***","level":"Moderate"},{"id":30,"question":"最近何してました？","answer":"What have you been up to lately?","tips":"***Wha*t** ~~have~~ ~~you~~ been *u*p ~~to~~ ***late*ly**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":31,"question":"あいつ性格悪いよね？（仲間内の会話）","answer":"That guy’s kind of a jerk, right?","tips":"~~That~~ *guy*’s ~~kind of a~~ *jer*k(↘) // **right**(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":32,"question":"明日こそ棚の中を片付ける","answer":"I’m definitely cleaning out the shelf tomorrow.","tips":"~~I’m~~ ***de*finitely** *clean*ing out ~~the~~ *she*lf **to*mor*row**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":33,"question":"先にどうぞ。次のに乗ります。","answer":"Go ahead, I’ll take the next one.","tips":"**Go** **a*head*** // ~~I’ll~~ take ~~the~~ **next** **one**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":34,"question":"(このエレベーターは)下に行きますよね？","answer":"This is going down, right?","tips":"~~This is~~ *go*ing **down**(↘) // **right**(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":35,"question":"気がついたら外がすっかり暗くなっていた。","answer":"Before I knew it, the sky had turned completely dark.","tips":"~~Before I~~ knew ~~it~~ // ~~the~~ **sky** ~~had~~ *tur*ned com*plete*ly ***dar*k**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":36,"question":"またこんな時間まで働いてしまった。","answer":"Once again, I ended up working until this late hour.","tips":"~~Once~~ ~~again~~ // I ***end*ed** up *work*ing ~~until~~ ~~this~~ ***la*te** *hou*r\n","level":"Moderate"},{"id":37,"question":"カフェを出た途端、お腹が痛くなった。","answer":"As soon as I left the café, I got a terrible stomachache.","tips":"~~As soon as I~~ left ~~the~~ **ca*fé*** // ~~I~~ got ~~a~~ *ter*rible ***sto*machache**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":38,"question":"近くのデパートのトイレに駆け込まなければならなかった。","answer":"I had to dash into a nearby department store’s restroom.","tips":"~~I~~ had ~~to~~ *da*sh // ~~into a~~ near*by* **de*part*ment** store’s // ***rest*room**","level":"Hard"},{"id":39,"question":"よくお腹痛くなるんだよね","answer":"I get stomachaches pretty often.","tips":"~~I~~ *ge*t *sto*mach*a*ches // ***pret*ty** *of*ten","level":"Beginner"},{"id":40,"question":"焼肉屋の24時間営業なんて気が狂ってるよ。","answer":"A 24-hour yakiniku restaurant?  That’s insane.","tips":"**A** ***24*-hour** **yaki*ni*ku** **res*tau*rant**(↗) // ~~That’s~~ **in*sane***(↘)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":41,"question":"誰が変な時間にそんなヘビーなもん食べるんだよ？","answer":"Who eats something that heavy at odd hours?","tips":"**Who** **eats** ~~something that~~ ***hea*vy** ~~at~~ **odd** **hours**(↗)\n","level":"Moderate"},{"id":42,"question":"ところがどっこい朝からお客が入ってる。","answer":"And yet—there are customers even in the morning!","tips":"~~And~~ **yet**(↘) // ~~there are~~ **cus*tom*ers** // ***e*ven** ~~in the~~ ***morn*ing**(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":43,"question":"お風呂に入りたい時に入れないのがヤダ","answer":"I hate it when I want to take a bath but can’t.","tips":"~~I~~ ***ha*te** ~~it~~ // ~~when I~~ *wa*nt ~~to~~ *ta*ke ~~a~~ ***ba*th** // ~~but~~ **can’t**","level":"Hard"},{"id":44,"question":"即座に英文を組み立てるスキルを養わねば。","answer":"I need to get better at forming English sentences on the spot.","tips":"~~I~~ need ~~to~~ get ***bet*ter** // ~~at~~ *form*ing ***Eng*lish** ***sen*tences** // ~~on the~~ **spot**\n","level":"Extreme"},{"id":45,"question":"今日は午前中家で制作の仕事をする。","answer":"This morning, I’ll be working on production tasks at home.","tips":"This ***morn*ing**(↗)// ~~I’ll be~~ *work*ing ~~on~~ **pro*duc*tion** *ta*sks ~~at~~ home(↘)\n","level":"Moderate"},{"id":46,"question":"それから、午後ITクラスの授業をして、夕方ミーティングに出席する。","answer":"Then I'll be teaching an IT class in the afternoon, and attending a meeting in the evening.","tips":"~~Then~~ ~~I’ll be~~ *teach*ing ~~an~~ **IT** **class** // ~~in the~~ **after*noon***(↗)// ~~and~~ at*tend*ing ~~a ***meet*ing** // ~~in the~~ ***e*vening**(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":47,"question":"いつスーパーに行こう。","answer":"When should I go to the supermarket?","tips":"**When** ~~should~~ ~~I~~ go ~~to the~~ ***su*permarket**(↘)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":48,"question":"このスケジュールで時間あるかな？","answer":"Do I even have time with this schedule?","tips":"Do ~~I~~ ***e*ven** ~~have~~ **time** // ~~with~~ ~~this~~ ***sched*ule**(↘)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":49,"question":"しばらく外出が続く","answer":"I’ll be going out a lot.","tips":"~~I’ll be~~ *go*ing out // ~~a~~ **lot**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":50,"question":"タクシーに乗るためにGCashにチャージしておかなきゃ。","answer":"I should top up my GCash for taxi fares.","tips":"~~I~~ should ***to*p** up ~~my~~ **G*Cash*** // ~~for~~ ***ta*xi** *fare*s\n","level":"Hard"},{"id":51,"question":"今月はお金使いすぎた。","answer":"I’ve spent way too much this month","tips":"~~I’ve~~ spent way **too** **much** // ~~this~~ **month**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":52,"question":"来月から財布の紐を締めていこう。","answer":"I'll be cutting back on spending next month.","tips":"~~I’ll be~~ *cut*ting back ~~on~~ ***spend*ing** // ne~~xt~~ month","level":"Moderate"},{"id":53,"question":"先方に今日使う教材を送らねば。","answer":"I need to send the materials for today’s lesson to them.","tips":"I need ~~to~~ send ~~the~~ **ma*te*rials** // ~~for~~ ***to*day’s** ***les*son** // ~~to~~ *the*m","level":"Extreme"},{"id":54,"question":"もう8時だ。","answer":"It's already eight o'clock.","tips":"~~It’s~~ al*read*y ***eigh*t** o’clock","level":"Beginner"},{"id":55,"question":"今日中にすべてのタスクが終わるのやら笑","answer":"I wonder if I'll get everything done today.","tips":"I ***won*der** ~~if~~ ~~I’ll~~ ge~~t~~ ***e*verything** done to*day*","level":"Moderate"},{"id":56,"question":"私は英語での数字をよく間違えるんだよね。","answer":"I often mess up numbers in English.","tips":"I ~~often~~ mess up ***num*bers** // ~~in~~ ***Eng*lish**","level":"#ERROR!"},{"id":57,"question":"先日もやらかした。","answer":"I made another mistake the other day.","tips":"I made ~~a~~ **a*no*ther** mis*take* ~~the~~ ***o*ther** day","level":"Moderate"},{"id":58,"question":"あぁ、恥ずかしい。","answer":"Ah, so embarrassing!","tips":"**Ah**, ~~so~~ **em*bar*rassing**!(↘)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":59,"question":"一階にある、ランドリーに洗濯を取りに行かなきゃ","answer":"I need to go downstairs to the laundry shop and pick up my clothes.","tips":"I need ~~to~~ go ***down*stairs** // ~~to the~~ ***laun*dry** shop // ~~and~~ *pi*ck up ~~my~~ ***clo*thes**","level":"Hard"},{"id":60,"question":"Githubには上げてます。","answer":"I’ve already uploaded it to GitHub.","tips":"~~I’ve~~ al*ready* up*loa*ded ~~it~~ ~~to~~ ***Git*Hub**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":61,"question":"念の為授業のMaterialをこちらにも送っておきますね。","answer":"But just in case, I’m sending the materials here as well.","tips":"But ~~just~~ ~~in~~ case(↗), // I’m *send*ing ~~the~~ **ma*te*rials** // ~~here~~ ~~as~~ well","level":"Hard"},{"id":62,"question":"近くのカフェがまだオープンしてなかった。","answer":"The nearby cafe wasn’t open yet.","tips":"~~The~~ near*by* **ca*fé*** // ~~wasn’t~~ ***o*pen** yet","level":"Beginner"},{"id":63,"question":"仕事前に軽食食べてコーヒー飲もうと思ったのに。","answer":"I was having a snack and coffee before work.","tips":"I ~~was~~ *hav*ing ~~a~~ **snack** ~~and~~ ***cof*fee** // ~~before~~ **work**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":64,"question":"仕方ないので、次に近いカフェに行った","answer":"Since there was no other choice, I went to the next closest café.  ","tips":"***Sin*ce** ~~there~~ ~~was~~ ~~no~~ ***o*ther** choice, // I went ~~to the~~ ***ne*xt** ***clos*est** **ca*fé***","level":"Extreme"},{"id":65,"question":"お気に入りのチーズのスナックが戻ってる。いいね！","answer":"My favorite cheesy snack is back! Awesome!","tips":"My fa*vor*ite ***chees*y*** snack // ~~is~~ **back**! // ***Awe*some**!","level":"Moderate"},{"id":66,"question":"たまにはいいことがあるもんだ","answer":"Sometimes good things do happen.","tips":"*Some*times **good** things **do** ***hap*pen**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":67,"question":"また、ボトルを落として粉々に割ってしまった。","answer":"I dropped the bottle and shattered it into pieces again.","tips":"I *dro*ppe~~d~~ ~~the~~ ***bot*tle** // ~~and~~ ***shat*tered** ~~it~~ ~~into~~ pie~~ces~~ **a*gain***","level":"Moderate"},{"id":68,"question":"自分のドジさに嫌気が差す。","answer":"I hate how clumsy I am!","tips":"I *ha*te ~~how~~ ***clum*sy** ~~I~~ *a*m!","level":"Beginner"},{"id":69,"question":"真夜中に床にほうきがけする羽目になった。","answer":"I ended up sweeping the floor at midnight.","tips":"I *end*ed up ***sweep*ing** ~~the~~ floor // ~~at~~ ***mid*night**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":70,"question":"窓から見える景色って大事だね","answer":"The view from the window really matters.","tips":"~~The~~ *vi*ew ~~from the~~ ***win*dow** // *real*ly ***mat*ters**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":71,"question":"数日前に徹底的に窓を掃除した。","answer":"A few days ago, I thoroughly cleaned the window.","tips":"~~A~~ few days ~~ago~~, I **thor*ough*ly** cleaned ~~the~~ ***win*dow**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":72,"question":"散歩から帰ってきて部屋に入った瞬間、自分の部屋じゃないかと思った。","answer":"The moment I walked in after my walk, I thought I'd entered the wrong unit.","tips":"~~The~~ *mo*ment I *walk*ed in // ~~after~~ ~~my~~ walk, // I thought ~~I’d~~ ***en*tered** ~~the~~ **wrong** *u*nit","level":"Extreme"},{"id":73,"question":"それでスムーズになるなら、現金で払えますよ。","answer":"I can pay in cash if that helps.","tips":"I ~~can~~ pay ~~in~~ **cash** // ~~if~~ ~~that~~ helps","level":"Extreme"},{"id":74,"question":"GCash払いはできますか？( accept )","answer":"Do you accept GCash?","tips":"~~Do~~ ~~you~~ ac*cept* **G*Cash***?","level":"Beginner"},{"id":75,"question":"カードで支払います。","answer":"I'll pay by card, please.","tips":"I’ll pay ~~by~~ ***car*d**,// please","level":"Beginner"},{"id":76,"question":"これをGCashで払います。","answer":"I'll use GCash for this.","tips":"I’ll use **G*Cash*** ~~for~~ this","level":"Beginner"},{"id":77,"question":"今日は現金で払います。","answer":"I'll be paying in cash today.","tips":"I’ll ~~be~~ *pay*ing ~~in~~ **cash** to*day*","level":"Beginner"},{"id":78,"question":"赤いカフェのすぐ近くでおろしてください。","answer":"Could you drop me off by the red café?","tips":"~~Could~~ you **drop** me off // ~~by~~ ~~the~~ **red** **ca*fé***","level":"Moderate"},{"id":79,"question":"赤いカフェの前でおろしてください。","answer":"Just drop me off in front of the red café, please.","tips":"~~Just~~ ***dro*p** me off // ~~in~~ ~~front~~ ~~of~~ ~~the~~ ***re*d** **ca*fé***,// please","level":"Extreme"},{"id":80,"question":"準備OKです、出発してください。","answer":"All set. You can go now.","tips":"~~All~~ ***se*t**. // ~~You~~ ~~can~~ **go** now","level":"Beginner"},{"id":81,"question":"こんにちは、〇〇です。あなたが私のドライバーですか？","answer":"Hi, 〇〇! You're my driver, right?","tips":"Hi, 〇〇! // ~~You’re~~ ~~my~~ ***dri*ver**(↘) ,// *righ*t? (↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":82,"question":"道知ってます。案内しますよ。","answer":"I know the way—I’ll guide you.","tips":"I know ~~the~~ **way** — I’ll ***gui*de** you","level":"Beginner"},{"id":83,"question":"ピンクの看板の前で止まってください","answer":"Just stop in front of the pink sign, please.","tips":"~~Just~~ **stop** ~~in~~ ~~front~~ ~~of~~ ~~the~~ **pink** **sign**, // please","level":"Moderate"},{"id":84,"question":"左手の駐車場に入ってください。","answer":"Turn into the parking lot to your left.","tips":"**Turn** ~~into~~ ~~the~~ ***park*ing** lot // ~~to~~ ~~your~~ **left**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":85,"question":"今日はエアコンクリーニング業者が来る予定だ","answer":"An air conditioning cleaning service is scheduled to come today.","tips":"~~An~~ **air** con*di*tioning ***clean*ing** *ser*vice // ~~is~~ *sche*duled ~~to~~ *co*me to*day*","level":"Hard"},{"id":86,"question":"今朝ねんのため私のエージェントにスケジュールを確認した。","answer":"This morning, I confirmed the schedule with my agent just in case.","tips":"This ***mor*ning**, I con*firm*ed ~~the~~ ***sched*ule** // ~~with~~ ~~my~~ ***a*gent** ~~just~~ ~~in~~ case","level":"Extreme"},{"id":87,"question":"まだ返事をもらっていません。","answer":"I haven’t heard back yet.","tips":"I ~~haven’t~~ ***hear*d** back ~~yet~~","level":"Beginner"},{"id":88,"question":"だからこういう業者は信用できない。","answer":"That's why I don’t trust service providers like this.","tips":"That’s why ~~I~~ don’t **trust** *ser*vice pro*vid*ers // ~~like~~ **this**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":89,"question":"いつも頭で思っていることで英作文を作った。","answer":"I turned my usual thoughts into an English composition.","tips":"I turned ~~my~~ ***u*sual** thoughts // ~~into~~ ~~an~~ ***Eng*lish** compo*si*tion","level":"Hard"},{"id":90,"question":"午前中だけで８３個もできた。","answer":"I ended up with 83 just this morning!","tips":"I ***end*ed** up ~~with~~ ***eigh*ty-three** // ~~just~~ ~~this~~ *morn*ing","level":"Moderate"},{"id":91,"question":"プログラマーは集中できる環境を作るのが大事。","answer":"Creating a distraction-free environment is essential for programmers to maintain focus.","tips":"Creating ~~a~~ dis*trac*tion-free en*vi*ronment // ~~is~~ es*sen*tial ~~for~~ pro*gram*mers // ~~to~~ *main*tain ***fo*cus**","level":"Hard"},{"id":92,"question":"はぁああ、今は自分のタスクに集中させてよ。。。","answer":"Come on, just let me focus on my task right now.","tips":"Come on, // just let me ***fo*cus** ~~on~~ ~~my~~ **task** ~~right~~ **now**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":93,"question":"彼らは昨日絶対私の部屋に来ないと確信していた。","answer":"I was convinced they hadn't shown up at my unit yesterday.","tips":"I ~~was~~ con*vince*d ~~they hadn’t~~ **shown** up ~~at~~ ~~my~~ ***u*nit** *yes*terday","level":"Extreme"},{"id":94,"question":"今日は部屋掃除のサービスの方がやってくる。楽しみだ。","answer":"The cleaning service is coming today—I'm looking forward to it!","tips":"~~The~~ *clean*ing *ser*vice ~~is~~ *com*ing to*day* — I’m ***look*ing** *for*ward ~~to~~ it","level":"Hard"},{"id":95,"question":"今更年期になったかも。","answer":"I might be going through the change these days...","tips":"I ~~might~~ ~~be~~ *go*ing through ~~the~~ **change** ~~these~~ days...","level":"Moderate"},{"id":96,"question":"私は別々の人に2回もすっぽかしを食らった。","answer":"I got stood up twice by two different people.","tips":"I ~~got~~ stood up **twice** // ~~by~~ two ***dif*ferent** *peo*ple","level":"Moderate"},{"id":97,"question":"人をすっぽかすのが許されるなんて、絶対に思うな！","answer":"Don't you dare think standing people up is acceptable!","tips":"Don’t you **dare** think ***stand*ing** *peo*ple up ~~is~~ **ac*cept*able**!","level":"Hard"},{"id":98,"question":"今日もすっぽかされるんじゃないかって心配になる。","answer":"I'm worried that I'll get stood up again today.","tips":"~~I’m~~ ***wor*ried** ~~that I’ll get~~ stood up **a*gain*** to*day*","level":"Moderate"},{"id":99,"question":"約束を守れる人がこの国のどこにいるの？","answer":"Where in this country can I find someone who actually keeps their promises?","tips":"~~Where in this~~ ***coun*try** ~~can I~~ find *some*one ~~who~~ ***ac*tually** keeps ~~their~~ ***pro*mises**?","level":"Hard"},{"id":100,"question":"昨日のレジ打ちは優秀やった。","answer":"The cashier yesterday was excellent.","tips":"~~The~~ ***cash*ier** *yes*terday ~~was~~ ***ex*cellent**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":101,"question":"同じタイプの電球を探している 。","answer":"I'm looking for the same type of light bulb.","tips":"~~I’m~~ *look*ing ~~for~~ ~~the~~ **same** type ~~of~~ **light** **bulb**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":102,"question":"メーカーのこだわりはない。","answer":"I don’t mind the brand.","tips":"I don’t ***min*d** ~~the~~ ***bran*d**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":103,"question":"自分の機嫌は自分で取ろう。","answer":"Keep yourself in a good mood.","tips":"*Kee*p ~~your~~self ~~in~~ ~~a~~ ***goo*d** *moo*d","level":"Beginner"},{"id":104,"question":"誰かの親切を当たり前だと思ってはいけない。","answer":"Never take someone's kindness for granted.","tips":"***Ne*ver** *ta*ke *some*one’s ***kind*ness** ~~for~~ ***gran*ted**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":105,"question":"自分の英語力をひけらかしてるね。","answer":"Being confident in your English is great.","tips":"**Be*ing** **con*fi*dent** ~~in~~ ~~your~~ **Eng*lish** ~~is~~ **great**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":106,"question":"でも自分より喋れない人にマウント取るのは良くないよ。","answer":"But don't make others feel small because of it.","tips":"But don’t **make** *o*thers feel small ~~because~~ ~~of~~ it","level":"Moderate"},{"id":107,"question":"痛、、、2箇所も口内炎できた。","answer":"Ouch! I got two canker sores...","tips":"***Ou*ch**! ~~I got~~ **two** ***can*ker** *sor*es...","level":"Beginner"},{"id":108,"question":"多分ビタミン不足のせいやね。","answer":"I think it's because of a lack of some kind of vitamin.","tips":"I **think** ~~it’s because of a~~ **lack** ~~of some~~ kind ~~of~~ ***vi*tamin**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":109,"question":"本当の友達がいなくなるよ(genuine)","answer":"Genuine friends will drift away.","tips":"***Gen*uine** *frie*nds ~~will~~ *dri*ft **a*way***","level":"Beginner"},{"id":110,"question":"本当の友達がいなくなるよ","answer":"You'll lose your real friends.","tips":"You’ll lo*se ~~your~~ ***rea*l** *frie*nds","level":"Beginner"},{"id":111,"question":"リアクションが見たいだけでしょ？","answer":"You just want to see the reaction, don't you?","tips":"~~You~~ just **want** ~~to~~ **see** ~~the~~ **re*ac*tion**,(↘)  // **don’t** you? (↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":112,"question":"絶対おもろいだろうからね(hilarious)","answer":"It's definitely gonna be hilarious!","tips":"~~It’s~~ ***def*initely** gonna ~~be~~ **hi*la*rious**!","level":"Beginner"},{"id":113,"question":"これは絶対おもろいだろうからね(no doubt!)","answer":"This is gonna be so funny, no doubt!","tips":"~~This is gonna be~~ **so** ***fun*ny**, ~~no~~ ***dou*bt**!","level":"Hard"},{"id":114,"question":"ちょっと頼みたいんだけど(favor)","answer":"I need a favor.","tips":"I need ~~a~~ ***fa*vor**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":115,"question":"ちょっとお願いしてもいい？","answer":"Can I ask you something?","tips":"~~Can~~ I *a*sk you ***some*thing**?","level":"Beginner"},{"id":116,"question":"ちょっと聞きたいんだけど(gotta)","answer":"I gotta ask you something.","tips":"I ~~gotta~~ *a*sk you ***some*thing**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":117,"question":"ちょっと聞いてもいい？(let)","answer":"Let me ask you something.","tips":"Let me *a*sk you ***some*thing**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":118,"question":"ちょっと質問がある","answer":"I have a quick question.","tips":"I have ~~a~~ *qui*ck ***ques*tion**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":119,"question":"言っていることではなくやっていることがその人の正体です","answer":"What people do, not what they say, is their true identity.","tips":"What ***peo*ple** **do**, // not what ~~they~~ **say**, // ~~is~~ ~~their~~ **true** **i*den*tity**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":120,"question":"あなたのことを嫌っている人と同じ数だけ味方もいる","answer":"For every person who dislikes you, there is an equal number who stand by your side.","tips":"~~For~~ ***e*very** ***per*son** // ~~who~~ dis*likes* you, (↗) // ~~there~~ ~~is~~ ~~an~~ ***e*qual** ***num*ber** // ~~who~~ ***stan*d** ~~by~~ ~~your~~ ***si*de**(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":121,"question":"誰しもがすべての人に好かれるとは限らない","answer":"Not everyone can be liked by everyone.","tips":"Not ***e*veryone** ~~can~~ ~~be~~ **liked** ~~by~~ ***e*veryone**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":122,"question":"うちのコンドではグリーストラップ清掃サービスが一社しか使えない。","answer":"Our condo only has one grease trap cleaning service.","tips":"~~Our~~ ***con*do** ***on*ly** has **one** ***grea*se** trap ***clean*ing** *ser*vice","level":"Hard"},{"id":123,"question":"他の業者を使うことは許可されてません。","answer":"we're not allowed to use any other providers.","tips":"~~We’re~~ **not** al*low*ed ~~to~~ use ~~any~~ **other** **pro*vid*ers**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":124,"question":"その他インターネットプロバイダーも一社しか使うことを許されてません。","answer":"Besides, we are only allowed to use one internet provider as well.","tips":"Be*si*des, ~~we~~ ~~are~~ ***on*ly** al*low*ed ~~to~~ use **one** ***in*ternet** pro*vid*er ~~as~~ **well**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":125,"question":"一社独占っておかしいよね？","answer":"Isn't it weird that there's only one company running everything?","tips":"***Isn*’t** it ***weir*d** ~~that~~ ~~there’s~~ ***on*ly** **one** ***com*pany** *run*ning ***e*verything**?(同意を求めたい↗)(怒ってる場合↘)","level":"Hard"},{"id":126,"question":"裏取引でもあったんじゃない？","answer":"Did they make some kind of backroom deal?","tips":"Did ~~they~~ **make** some kind ~~of~~ ***back*room** **deal**?(↘)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":127,"question":"足元悪すぎて靴がドロドロになった","answer":"The ground was terrible, and my shoes got muddy.","tips":"~~The~~ **ground** ~~was~~ ***ter*rible**, ~~and~~ ~~my~~ **shoes** ~~got~~ ***mud*dy**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":128,"question":"突然の雨でみんなテントの下に避難した。","answer":"The sudden rain made everyone take shelter under the tent.","tips":"~~The~~ ***sud*den** **rain** made ***e*veryone** take ***shel*ter** ~~under~~ ~~the~~ **tent**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":129,"question":"2倍サイズはありますか？","answer":"Is there a double-sized version?","tips":"Is there ~~a~~ ***dou*ble**-*si*zed *ver*sion?(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":130,"question":"これは裏メニューですよ！","answer":"This is an off-menu!","tips":"This is ~~an~~ **off**-*me*nu!","level":"Beginner"},{"id":131,"question":"人は若いだけで価値がある","answer":"Being young is inherently valuable","tips":"***Be*ing** ***you*ng** ~~is~~ in*her*ently ***val*uable**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":132,"question":"見た目の美しさはいずれ失う","answer":"Looks don't last forever.","tips":"***Loo*ks** // don’t ***la*st** // **for*ev*er**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":133,"question":"だから我々は人間性と知性を磨かなければならない","answer":"That’s why we must cultivate our humanity and intelligence.","tips":"That’s why ~~we~~ must ***cul*tivate** ~~our~~ **hu*man*ity** and **in*tel*ligence**","level":"Hard"},{"id":134,"question":"人生は決断の連続","answer":"Life is a continuous chain of choices.","tips":"**Life** // ~~is~~ ~~a~~ **con*tin*uous** **chain** ~~of~~ **choices**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":135,"question":"いいね、賛成！(sound)","answer":"Sounds good to me.","tips":"*Soun*ds ***goo*d** ~~to~~ me","level":"Beginner"},{"id":136,"question":"考えてみるね。","answer":"I’ll think about it.","tips":"~~I’ll~~ ***thin*k** ~~about~~ ***i*t**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":137,"question":"あとで教えてね。","answer":"Let me know later.","tips":"*Le*t me *kno*w *la*ter","level":"Beginner"},{"id":138,"question":"それは見てなかった。","answer":"I didn’t see that.","tips":"I **didn’t** *se*e ~~that~~","level":"Beginner"},{"id":139,"question":"それはすごく納得できる。","answer":"That makes a lot of sense.","tips":"That ***ma*kes** ~~a~~ ***lo*t** ~~of~~ ***se*nse**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":140,"question":"完全に同意するよ。","answer":"I totally agree with you.","tips":"I ***to*tally** a*gree* ~~with~~ *yo*u","level":"Beginner"},{"id":141,"question":"一緒に解決しよう。","answer":"Let’s figure this out together.","tips":"Let’s *fig*ure ~~this~~ *ou*t **to*geth*er**\n","level":"Beginner"},{"id":142,"question":"今日は助けてくれてありがとう。","answer":"I appreciate your help today.","tips":"I **ap*pre*ciate** ~~your~~ *hel*p to*day*","level":"Beginner"},{"id":143,"question":"それ、いいね！やるよ！","answer":"I’m down for that.","tips":"I’m ***dow*n** ~~for~~ *tha*t","level":"Beginner"},{"id":144,"question":"あとで返答するね。","answer":"I’ll get back to you.","tips":"~~I’ll~~ ***ge*t** *ba*ck ~~to~~ *yo*u","level":"Beginner"},{"id":145,"question":"もう一度説明してくれる？(once more)","answer":"Can you explain that once more?","tips":"~~Can you~~ **ex*plain*** tha~~t~~ *on*ce *mo*re?","level":"Beginner"},{"id":146,"question":"聞き取れなかったので、もう一度言ってくれますか？","answer":"I didn’t catch that. Can you say it again?","tips":"I ~~didn’t~~ **catch** ~~that~~. ~~Can you~~ **say** ~~it~~ **a*gain***?","level":"Extreme"},{"id":147,"question":"人々は信じられないほど強い。","answer":"People are incredibly resilient.","tips":"***Peo*ple** ~~are~~ in*cred*ibly **re*sil*ient**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":148,"question":"本当に尊敬するよ","answer":"I really admire you.","tips":"I ***real*ly** **ad*mire*** ~~you~~","level":"Beginner"},{"id":149,"question":"私は仕事で最善を尽くそうと頑張ってるよね？","answer":"I'm striving to do my best at work, aren't I?","tips":"~~I'm~~ ***striv*ing** ~~to~~ do ~~my~~ **best** ~~at~~ *wor*k, ~~aren’t~~ I?","level":"Extreme"},{"id":150,"question":"もう少しウイスキーを足してもらえますか？","answer":"Could you add a bit more whiskey?","tips":"~~Could you~~ **add** ~~a~~ bit more ***whis*key**?","level":"Moderate"},{"id":151,"question":"ちょっと味気なく感じます。","answer":"It feels a bit bland.","tips":"~~It~~ *fee*ls ~~a~~ bi~t~ ***bla*nd**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":152,"question":"ほとんどアルコールの味がしない","answer":"I can barely taste the alcohol.","tips":"I ~~can barely~~ *ta*ste ~~the~~ ***al*cohol**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":153,"question":"マイルドすぎる感じがする","answer":"It feels too mild.","tips":"~~It~~ *fee*ls **too** *mi*ld","level":"Beginner"},{"id":154,"question":"味が薄い／弱い","answer":"It tastes weak.","tips":"~~It~~ *ta*stes ***wea*k**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":155,"question":"生理始まった","answer":"My menstruation started today.","tips":"~~My~~ **menstru*a*tion** *star*ted to*day*","level":"Beginner"},{"id":156,"question":"生理なんよね","answer":"I have my period today.","tips":"I have ~~my~~ **pe*ri*od** to*day*","level":"Beginner"},{"id":157,"question":"便秘三日目です","answer":"I've been constipated for three days.","tips":"~~I’ve been~~ **consti*pa*ted** ~~for~~ **three** **days**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":158,"question":"便秘三日目です（ちょっと濁す）","answer":"I haven't had a bowel movement in three days.","tips":"~~I haven’t~~ had ~~a~~ ***bow*el** ***mo*vement** ~~in~~ **three** **days**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":159,"question":"まだ今月生理が来ていない。","answer":"My period hasn't come yet this month.","tips":"My **pe*ri*od** ~~hasn’t~~ come ~~yet~~ ~~this~~ **month**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":160,"question":"彼は他人の時間をどう考えているんだ？","answer":"How does he value other people's time?","tips":"~~How does~~ he ***va*lue** ~~other~~ ***peo*ple’s** **time**?  ","level":"Moderate"},{"id":161,"question":"彼は人の時間を全く考えていない。","answer":"He has no regard for people's time.","tips":"He ~~has~~ no **re*gard*** // ~~for~~ ***peo*ple’s** **time**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":162,"question":"（最近）英のボキャブラリーを増やそうと頑張っています。","answer":"I've been up to trying to increase my English vocabulary.","tips":"~~I’ve~~ been ~~up~~ ~~to~~ ***try*ing** // ~~to~~ **in*crease*** ~~my~~ ***Eng*lish** **vo*ca*bulary**","level":"Hard"},{"id":163,"question":"12時までに以下のリクエストをマージしてもらえますか？","answer":"Could you merge the following request by 12:00 pm, pls?","tips":"~~Could you~~ **merge** ~~the~~ ***fol*lowing** **re*quest*** // ~~by~~ **twelve** ~~pm~~ ~~pls~~?","level":"Hard"},{"id":164,"question":"12時までこのリクエストをマージしてもらえますか？","answer":"Please merge this request by noon. Thanks!","tips":"**Please** **merge** ~~this~~ **re*quest*** // ~~by~~ **noon**. // ~~Thanks~~!","level":"Moderate"},{"id":165,"question":"最近実店舗減ってるよね？","answer":"Brick-and-mortar stores decreased recently.","tips":"**Brick-~**~~and~~-***mor*tar** stores // decreased // ***re*cently**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":166,"question":"電話切って！","answer":"Cut the call.","tips":"***Cu*t** ~~the~~ ***ca*ll**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":167,"question":"英語が喋れるふりをしているだけ、でも実が違う","answer":"I just pretend as if I were fluent in English, but in reality, I'm not.","tips":"~~I just~~ **pre*tend*** // ~~as~~ ~~if~~ ~~I~~ ~~were~~ ***flu*ent** ~~in~~ ***Eng*lish**,(↗)// ~~but~~ ~~in~~ **re*a*lity**,(↗) //~~I’m~~ **not**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":168,"question":"英語が苦手な日本人やフィリピン人でも簡単に騙される","answer":"Even Japanese people and Filipinos who struggle with English easily believe that.","tips":"Even ***Ja*panese** ~~people~~ ~~and~~ **Fili*pi*nos** // ~~who~~ *strug*gle ~~with~~ ***Eng*lish** // easily **be*lieve*** ~~that~~","level":"Hard"},{"id":169,"question":"それが超面白い","answer":"That's insanely fun!","tips":"That’s **in*sane*ly** **fun**!","level":"Beginner"},{"id":170,"question":"あいついつも女の子をナンパしているよ（しつこい）","answer":"He's always hitting on girls.","tips":"He’s ***al*ways** ***hit*ting** ~~on~~ *gir*ls","level":"Beginner"},{"id":171,"question":"あいついつも女の子をナンパしているよ（積極的try）","answer":"He's always trying to pick up girls.","tips":"~~He’s~~ ***al*ways** *try*ing ~~to~~ pick up **girls**.","level":"Moderate"},{"id":172,"question":"あいついつも女の子をナンパしているよ（軽い）","answer":"He's always flirting with girls.","tips":"~~He’s~~ ***al*ways** *flirt*ing ~~with~~ *gir*ls.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":173,"question":"その熱意を英語の勉強に捧げればいいのに","answer":"He should devote that enthusiasm to studying English instead.","tips":"He should **de*vo*te** that **en*thu*siasm** // ~~to~~ *stu*dying ***Eng*lish** in*stead*.","level":"Hard"},{"id":174,"question":"彼女は神経質だと思う（敏感）","answer":"I feel like she's overly sensitive.","tips":"I *fee*l ~~like~~ ~~she’s~~ **o*ver*ly** *sen*sitive.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":175,"question":"私の姉は潔癖症です","answer":"My older sister is very particular about cleanliness.","tips":"~~My~~ *ol*der ***sis*ter** ~~is~~ very **par*tic*ular** // ~~about~~ **clean*li*ness**.","level":"Moderate"},{"id":176,"question":"私なりに助けようとしていたんだよ。","answer":"In my defense, I was just trying to help.","tips":"~~In my~~ **de*fen*se**, // ~~I was just~~ *try*ing ~~to~~ **help**.","level":"Extreme"},{"id":177,"question":"彼は別れた後、かなり落ち込んでいる。","answer":"He's really screwed up after the breakup.","tips":"~~He’s~~ *rea*lly ***screwed** up // ~~after the~~ ***break*up**.","level":"Moderate"},{"id":178,"question":"彼女が来るといつもめちゃめちゃにする","answer":"She always screws up when she comes.","tips":"She ***al*ways** **screws** up // ~~when~~ she **comes**.","level":"Moderate"},{"id":179,"question":"噂ではあいつら付き合ってるみたい。","answer":"Word is, they're seeing each other.","tips":"***Wor*d** ~~is~~, // ~~they’re~~ ***see*ing** *ea*ch *oth*er.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":180,"question":"彼と今付き合っています。(relationship)","answer":"I'm now in a relationship with him.","tips":"I’m **now** // ~~in a~~ **re*la*tion*ship** ~~with~~ him.","level":"Moderate"},{"id":181,"question":"彼と付き合い始めました。(date)","answer":"I started dating him.","tips":"~~I~~ *star*ted ***da*ting** him.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":182,"question":"私たち、正式に付き合うことになりました。","answer":"We just became official.","tips":"~~We~~ ~~just~~ be*came* **of*fi*cial**.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":183,"question":"二人は正式に付き合うことになったって聞いたよ。","answer":"I heard they made it official.","tips":"**I heard** // ~~they~~ made ~~it~~ **of*fi*cial**.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":184,"question":"日本人女性は自分からあまり男性を誘わない。","answer":"Japanese women tend not to ask men out themselves.","tips":"***Ja*panese** *wo*men // tend **not** ~~to~~ **ask** men out ~~themselves~~.","level":"Hard"},{"id":185,"question":"する（誘う）ときは気があるときだよ","answer":"When they do, it usually means they're interested.","tips":"When ~~they~~ *do*, // ~~it~~ *usually* means // ~~they’re~~ ***in*terested**.","level":"Hard"},{"id":186,"question":"マッチングアプリは詐欺と虚像で満たされてる","answer":"Dating apps are filled with deception and illusions.","tips":"***Da*ting** apps //~~*are~~ filled ~~with~~ **de*cep*tion** ~~and~~ **il*lu*sions**.","level":"Moderate"},{"id":187,"question":"本当の出会いがあるとしたら","answer":"If a genuine connection does happen","tips":"~~If a~~ **ge*nu*ine** con*nec*tion // **does** *hap*pen","level":"Beginner"},{"id":188,"question":"宝くじが当たるくらいの確率だよ","answer":"The odds are about the same as winning the lottery.","tips":"~~The~~ **odds** ~~are about the~~ same // ~~as~~ *win*ning ~~the~~ **lot*ter*y**.","level":"Hard"},{"id":189,"question":"時間の無駄だよ。","answer":"it's a waste of time.","tips":"~~It’s a~~ waste ~~of~~ **time**.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":190,"question":"人間も生き物だから普通にしてたら太らないよ","answer":"Since humans are living beings, they won’t gain weight as long as they live naturally.","tips":"Since ***hu*mans** ~~are~~ ***li*ving** beings, // ~~they~~ **won’t** gain ***weigh*t** // ~~as~~ long ~~as~~ ~~they~~ live ***na*turally**.","level":"Extreme"},{"id":191,"question":"極端に太った動物を見たいことありますか？","answer":"Have you ever seen an extremely overweight wild animal?","tips":"~~Have you~~ ever seen ~~an~~ **ex*treme*ly** over*weight* wild ***a*nimal**?","level":"Hard"},{"id":192,"question":"ストレス、飽食、あれこれ。","answer":"Stress, overeating, blah, blah, blah.","tips":"**Stress**, **over*eat*ing**, blah, blah, blah.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":193,"question":"ポイントは我々の生活はすでに普通じゃないということです","answer":"The point is, our lifstyle is no longer natural.","tips":"~~The~~ **point** ~~is~~, // ~~our~~ ***life*style** ~~is~~ no longer *na*tural.","level":"Moderate"},{"id":194,"question":"準備しなきゃ","answer":"I have to be ready.","tips":"I have ~~to be~~ ***rea*dy**.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":195,"question":"責任を人に押し付けないでよ","answer":"Don't pass the buck!!","tips":"Don’t **pass** ~~the~~ **buck**!!","level":"Beginner"},{"id":196,"question":"助手席座ってもいい？","answer":"Can I ride shotgun?","tips":"~~Can I~~ ride ***shot*gun**?(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":197,"question":"助手席は私のもの！","answer":"I call shotgun!","tips":"~~I~~ *call* **shot*gun**!","level":"Beginner"},{"id":198,"question":"二日酔いは前夜の楽しい時間の代償","answer":"A hangover is the price you pay for a good time the night before.","tips":"~~A~~ ***hang*over**  // ~~is the~~ price ~~you~~ pay ~~for a~~ **good time** ~~the~~ night be*fore*.","level":"Extreme"},{"id":199,"question":"彼を説得してもらえますか？","answer":"Could you try convincing him?","tips":"~~Could you~~ try **con*vinc*ing** him?(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":200,"question":"さきに請求してもらえますか？","answer":"Can you bill me in advance?","tips":"~~Can you~~ bill me ~~in~~ ad*vance*?","level":"Beginner"},{"id":201,"question":"揃える資料はありますか？","answer":"Do I need to gather any documents?","tips":"~~Do I~~ need ~~to~~ *gath*er any ***doc*uments**?(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":202,"question":"銀行振込で支払います","answer":"I will be paying by bank transfer.","tips":"~~I will be~~ *pay*ing ~~by~~ **bank** *trans*fer.","level":"Moderate"},{"id":203,"question":"お邪魔してすみません","answer":"Sorry to bother you.","tips":"***So*rry** ~~to~~ *bo*ther you.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":204,"question":"少し待ってもらえますか？(give)","answer":"Can you give me a second？","tips":"~~Can you~~ give me ~~a~~ *se*cond?(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":205,"question":"少し待ってもらえますか？（hold）","answer":"Hold on a sec.","tips":"**Hold** ~~on a~~ sec.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":206,"question":"何だったのか、よく分からない…","answer":"I don't know what it was...","tips":"~~I don’t~~ // know what ~~it~~ was...","level":"Beginner"},{"id":207,"question":"どうやってそれを知ったの？","answer":"How did you know that?","tips":"How ~~did you~~ **know** that?(↘)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":208,"question":"偉大な知恵は何世代にも渡って人々から受け継がれています。","answer":"The great wisdom has been passed down by people for generations.","tips":"~~The~~ **great** *wis*dom ~~has been~~ passed down ~~by~~ *peo*ple ~~for~~ **gen*e*ra*tions**.","level":"Hard"},{"id":209,"question":"昨日、2つのアロマオイルを買いました。","answer":"I bought two vials of aroma oil yesterday.","tips":"~~The~~ **great** *wis*dom // passed down ~~by~~ *peo*ple ~~for~~ **gen*e*ra*tions**.","level":"Moderate"},{"id":210,"question":"昔から続いている療法は信頼がおける","answer":"Therapies practiced since ancient times must be reliable.","tips":"***Ther*apies** *prac*ticed ~~since~~ ***an*cient** times // must ~~be~~ re*li*a*ble.  ","level":"Hard"},{"id":211,"question":"あの噂をまだ信じている人がいるなんて信じられない！","answer":"It blows my mind that people still believe that rumor.","tips":"~~It~~ blows ~~my~~ mind // ~~that~~ *peo*ple still **be*lieve*** ~~that~~ *ru*mor.  ","level":"Hard"},{"id":212,"question":"あなたの論理に基づけば、この決定は理にかなっている。","answer":"On your logic, this decision makes sense.","tips":"~~On your~~ *log*ic, // this **de*ci*sion** makes sense.  ","level":"Moderate"},{"id":213,"question":"1つ条件がある。誰にも言わないこと。","answer":"One condition: you can't tell anyone.","tips":"**One** con*di*tion: // you **can’t** tell *a*nyone.  ","level":"Beginner"},{"id":214,"question":"彼は昨夜、泥酔していた。","answer":"He was drunk as a skunk last night.","tips":"He ~~was~~ drunk ~~as a~~ skunk last night.","level":"Extreme"},{"id":215,"question":"彼はいつも何かについて疑心暗鬼になっている。","answer":"He's always paranoid about something.","tips":"~~He’s~~ *al*ways ***pa*ranoid** ~~about~~ *some*thing.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":216,"question":"宇宙人はいると思うけど、ただの仮説だよ。","answer":"I think aliens exist, but it's just a theory.","tips":"I think ***a*liens** ex*ist*, // ~~but it’s~~ just ~~a~~ ***the*ory**. ","level":"Moderate"},{"id":217,"question":"彼の性格にはいくつかの側面がある。","answer":"His personality has several dimensions.","tips":"~~His~~ **person*a*lity** ~~has~~ *se*veral di*men*sions.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":218,"question":"昔みたいに徹夜できないよ。","answer":"I can't stay up all night like I used to.","tips":"~~I~~ **can’t** stay up **all** night // ~~like I~~ used ~~to~~.  ","level":"Hard"},{"id":219,"question":"もう20歳じゃない。","answer":"I'm not 20 anymore.","tips":"~~I’m~~ not **twenty** *a*nymore.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":220,"question":"いや、適当に作った話だよ。","answer":"Nah, I'm just making it up.","tips":"Nah, ~~I’m~~ just ***mak*ing** ~~it~~ up.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":221,"question":"気が狂いそうだ。","answer":"I'm going out of mind.","tips":"~~I’m~~ *go*ing ~~out of~~ mind.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":222,"question":"一体何が起こっているんだ？（in the hell）","answer":"What in the hell is going on?","tips":"**What** ~~in the~~ **hell** ~~is~~ *go*ing **on**(↘)","level":"Hard"},{"id":223,"question":"もう十分な時間が経った","answer":"It's been long enough.","tips":"~~It’s been~~ long e*nough*.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":224,"question":"彼を調査させている","answer":"I'm having him checked out.","tips":"~~I’m~~ *hav*ing ~~him~~ checked out.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":225,"question":"話を遮って申し訳ないですが、一言いいですか？","answer":"Sorry to interrupt, but can I say something?","tips":"***So*rry** ~~to~~ inter*rupt* // ~~but can I~~ say *some*thing(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":226,"question":"これはひどいアイデアだ","answer":"This is a terrible idea.","tips":"This ~~is~~ ~~a~~ ***ter*ible** i*dea*.","level":"Beginner"},{"id":227,"question":"保証はできませんが、大丈夫なはずです。","answer":"I can't guarantee it, but it should be OK.","tips":"I can’t guaran*tee* ~~it~~(↗) // ~~but it~~ should ~~be~~ **OK**.","level":"Extreme"},{"id":228,"question":"一度に一人ずつ、いいね？","answer":"One at a time, all right, you?","tips":"**One** ~~at a~~ time(↘) // **all** right(↗) // **you**(↗)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":229,"question":"テディはセオドア・ルーズベルトの愛称で、彼は26代目アメリカ大統領です。","answer":"Teddy is short for Theodore Roosevelt, who was the 26th president of the United States.","tips":"**Teddy** ~~is~~ short ~~for~~ *The*odore ***Roose*velt**(↘) // ~~who was~~ ~~the~~ **26th** *pres*ident ~~of the~~ U*ni*ted **States**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":230,"question":"それが何であれ、気にしないで。","answer":"Whatever the thing is, just ignore it.","tips":"**What*ever*** ~~the~~ thing ~~is~~(↘) // ~~just~~ ig*nore* ~~it~~.","level":"Moderate"},{"id":231,"question":"多分我々は一生人との関わりの悩みに人生を費やすんだろうね","answer":"Maybe we’ll spend our entire lives navigating the complexities of human relationships.","tips":"***May*be** ~~we’ll~~ spend ~~our~~ ***en*tire** lives // *nav*igating ~~the~~ **com*plex*ities** ~~of~~ *hu*man re*la*tionships","level":"Extreme"},{"id":232,"question":"好きな人といるだけでパワースポット（source of powerful energy）になる","answer":"Being with the people you love turns any place into a source of powerful energy.","tips":"*Be*ing ~~with~~ ~~the~~ *peo*ple ~~you~~ **love** // turns ~~any~~ place ~~into~~ ~~a~~ source ~~of~~ *pow*erful ***en*ergy**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":233,"question":"重要なのは贈り物そのものではなく、それをくれる人だ。","answer":"It's not the gift itself that matters, but the person who gives it to you.","tips":"~~It’s~~ not ~~the~~ gift it*self* that ***mat*ters** // but ~~the~~ *per*son ~~who~~ gives ~~it~~ ~~to~~ **you**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":234,"question":"お金の奴隷になってはいけない。","answer":"You must not become a slave to money.","tips":"You must not be*come* ~~a~~ **slave** ~~to~~ *mon*ey","level":"Moderate"},{"id":235,"question":"いろいろな食材が乗ったプレートはありますか？","answer":"Do you have a platter with a mix of different foods?","tips":"~~Do~~ you have ~~a~~ ***plat*ter** // ~~with~~ ~~a~~ mix ~~of~~ *dif*ferent **foods**(↗)","level":"Hard"},{"id":236,"question":"メニューに載っている正確な名前を覚えていません","answer":"I don't remember the exact name on the menu.","tips":"~~I don’t~~ **re*mem*ber** ~~the~~ **ex*act*** name ~~on~~ ~~the~~ menu","level":"Moderate"},{"id":237,"question":"メニューでは何と書いてあったか忘れました","answer":"I forgot what it's called on the menu.","tips":"I for*got* what ~~it’s~~ called ~~on~~ ~~the~~ menu","level":"Moderate"},{"id":238,"question":"バカにしないで！","answer":"Don't make fun of me!","tips":"Don’t make fun ~~of~~ **me**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":239,"question":"からかうのはやめて","answer":"Stop mocking me.","tips":"Stop ***mock*ing** me","level":"Beginner"},{"id":240,"question":"私を愚か者扱いしないで！","answer":"Don't treat me like a fool!","tips":"Don’t treat me ~~like a~~ **fool**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":241,"question":"お知らせいたします","answer":"Please be advised","tips":"**Please** ~~be~~ *ad*vised","level":"Beginner"},{"id":242,"question":"到着予定時刻は午後の早い時間帯です。","answer":"ETA will be early afternoon.","tips":"**ETA** ~~will be~~ *ear*ly after*noon*","level":"Beginner"},{"id":243,"question":"みんな他人について好き勝手言うよね","answer":"People say whatever comes to mind about others.","tips":"***Peo*ple** say **what*ever*** comes ~~to~~ mind ~~about~~ *oth*ers","level":"Moderate"},{"id":244,"question":"ハーフサイズの提供はありますか？","answer":"Do you have a half-size portion?","tips":"~~Do you~~ have ~~a~~ *half*-size ***por*tion**(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":245,"question":"以前はハーフサイズを注文できました。","answer":"Before, I could order the half-size portion.","tips":"**Be*fore***, ~~I could~~ *or*der ~~the~~ *half*-size **por*tion**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":246,"question":"人間の悩みはすべて対人関係に起因する","answer":"All human troubles stem from interpersonal relationships.","tips":"All *hu*man ***trou*bles** stem ~~from~~ inter*per*sonal re*la*tionships","level":"Moderate"},{"id":247,"question":"日本は江戸時代約300年戦争のない時代が続いた","answer":"Japan experienced nearly 300 years of peace during the Edo era, with no civil wars.","tips":"**Ja*pan*** ex*per*ienced *near*ly **three** *hun*dred years ~~of~~ peace ~~during~~ ~~the~~ ***E*do** era(↗)// ~~with~~ no ***ci*vil** wars(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":248,"question":"この史実はあの国の規模で他に類を見ない","answer":"This historical fact is unparalleled for a country of that scale.","tips":"This **his*tor*ical** fact ~~is~~ un*pa*ralleled ~~for~~ ~~a~~ *coun*try ~~of~~ ~~that~~ **scale**","level":"Hard"},{"id":249,"question":"人の話を聞くときも自分が話をするときも事実と意見を分けるようにする","answer":"Make sure to distinguish between facts and opinions, both when listening and when speaking.","tips":"Make sure ~~to~~ *dis*tinguish ~~between~~ **facts** ~~and~~ **o*pin*ions** (↗)// both ~~when~~ *lis*tening ~~and~~ ~~when~~ *speak*ing(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":250,"question":"人の話を鵜呑みにしない","answer":"Don’t blindly accept what people say.","tips":"Don’t ***blind*ly** ac*cept* what *peo*ple say","level":"Extreme"},{"id":251,"question":"（人は）考えなしに無責任に言うからね","answer":"As they often speak irresponsibly without thinking.","tips":"~~As they~~ *of*ten speak **irre*spon*sibly** // with*out* *think*ing","level":"Moderate"},{"id":252,"question":"友達から誘われたらできるだけ参加するようにしている","answer":"I make an effort to participate whenever my friends ask me to.","tips":"~~I~~ make ~~an~~ *ef*fort ~~to~~ **par*tic*ipate** // when*ev*er ~~my~~ **friends** ask ~~me to~~","level":"Extreme"},{"id":253,"question":"熱がどんどん上がってます。どうやら風邪を引いたようです","answer":"My fever is gradually getting worse. Apparently, I’ve caught a really bad cold.","tips":"~~My~~ ***fe*ver** ~~is~~ grad*u*ally *get*ting **worse** // Ap*par*ently(↗),// ~~I’ve~~ caught a *real*ly bad **cold**(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":254,"question":"これ以上悪くならないよ","answer":"Couldn't be worse.","tips":"Couldn’t ~~be~~ worse","level":"Beginner"},{"id":255,"question":"それ次第だね","answer":"It depends.","tips":"~~It~~ de*pends*","level":"Beginner"},{"id":256,"question":"よくコリアン食料品店に行くよ。豆腐やその他日本食に似たものがあるからね。","answer":"I often go to a korean grocery store. They have tofu and other stuff like Japanese food.","tips":"I *of*ten go ~~to~~ a Ko*re*an ***gro*cery** store // ~~They~~ have ***to*fu** and *oth*er stuff ~~like~~ Japa*ne*se food","level":"Extreme"},{"id":257,"question":"私は一体何を見させられているんだ？","answer":"I was like, \"What am I even being made to watch?!\"","tips":"~~I was~~ like, // “**What** ~~am I~~ ***e*ven** *be*ing made ~~to~~ **watch**?!”","level":"Extreme"},{"id":258,"question":"最高にうまくいってる","answer":"Couldn't be better","tips":"Couldn’t ~~be~~ *be*tter","level":"Beginner"},{"id":259,"question":"確かじゃないけど、彼はその日予定があるって言ってたと思う","answer":"I'm not sure, but I believe he said he had an appointment that day.","tips":"~~I’m~~ not sure, // ~~but I~~ be*lieve* ~~he~~ said ~~he had an~~ **ap*point*ment** ~~that~~ day","level":"Extreme"},{"id":260,"question":"たぶんすごく面白いに違いないと思う(sure)","answer":"I'm pretty sure it must be hilarious.","tips":"~~I’m~~ ***pret*ty** sure // ~~it~~ must ~~be~~ **hi*lar*i*ous**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":261,"question":"言いたいことわかる？","answer":"You know what I'm saying?","tips":"~~You~~ know what ~~I’m~~ ***say*ing**?(↘)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":262,"question":"わかる？（get）","answer":"You get me?","tips":"~~You~~ get me?(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":263,"question":"もし日本に戻るとしたら、どのくらい滞在しますか？","answer":"Let's say you went back to Japan—how long would you stay?","tips":"Let’s say ~~you~~ went back ~~to~~ **Ja*pan*** — // how long ~~would you~~ stay?(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":264,"question":"今日はどちらかというとイタリアンの気分","answer":"I'm feeling more like Italian today.","tips":"~~I’m~~ *feel*ing more ~~like~~ **I*tal*ian** to*day*","level":"Beginner"},{"id":265,"question":"なんかイタリアンっぽいものが食べたい気分","answer":"I'm in the mood for something more like Italian.","tips":"~~I’m in the~~ mood ~~for~~ *some*thing more ~~like~~ **I*tal*ian**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":266,"question":"しょうがない。","answer":"It is what it is.","tips":"~~It is~~ what ~~it is~~","level":"Beginner"},{"id":267,"question":"3年ぶりに両親に会った。","answer":"I saw my parents for the first time in 3 years.","tips":"~~I~~ saw ~~my~~ *pa*rents // ~~for the~~ **first** time ~~in~~ three years","level":"Extreme"},{"id":268,"question":"ヤカンがシューシュー言ってませんか？","answer":"Can we hear the kettle was hissing?","tips":"~~Can we~~ hear ~~the~~ *ket*tle ~~was~~ *hiss*ing?(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":269,"question":"ええ、（それを）切らなきゃね","answer":"Yeah, need to turn it off.","tips":"Yeah, // need ~~to~~ turn ~~it~~ **off**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":270,"question":"なんて生き物？","answer":"Holy shit???! What the hell is this creepy creature?!","tips":"***Ho*ly** **shit**???! // What ~~the~~ **hell** ~~is~~ this *cree*py **crea*ture**?!","level":"Moderate"},{"id":271,"question":"もう15日を過ぎてるよ。","answer":"It's well past the 15th now.","tips":"~~It’s~~ **well** past ~~the~~ **fif*teen*th** **now**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":272,"question":"今日の授業の目的は機能ごとにファイルを整理することですよね？","answer":"The purpose of today’s class is to organize files by their functions, correct?","tips":"~~The~~ ***pur*pose** ~~of~~ to*day’s* class // ~~is to~~ **or*gan*ize** files ~~by their~~ *func*tions(↘),// cor*rect*?(↗)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":273,"question":"あのとき英語でなんて言えばよかったんだ？っていう思う瞬間が無限にあります","answer":"I constantly find myself thinking, 'What should I have said in English at that moment?","tips":"~~I~~ *con*stantly find my*self* ***think*ing**,(↗) // **What** ~~should I have~~ said ~~in~~ *Eng*lish ~~at that~~ *mo*ment?’(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":274,"question":"1216のLazadaのパッケージ2個届いてませんか？","answer":"Did the two Lazada packages for 1216 get delivered?","tips":"~~Did the~~ **two** La*za*da *pack*ages ~~for~~ ***twel*ve-six*teen*** get de*liv*ered?(↗)","level":"Hard"},{"id":275,"question":"OSによっては、いくつかの文字は消えたり正しく表示されなかったりします。","answer":"Depending on the OS, some characters may not be displayed correctly and might be hidden.","tips":"De*pend*ing ~~on the~~ **O*S***,(↗)// ~~some~~ *char*acters ~~may~~ not ~~be~~ dis*played* cor*rect*ly ~~and~~ ~~might be~~ *hid*den(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":276,"question":"OSが文字コードを読み込めないから","answer":"Because the OS can't recognize its encoding.","tips":"Be*cause* ~~the~~ **O*S*** can’t *re*cognize ~~its~~ en*cod*ing","level":"Moderate"},{"id":277,"question":"どれでも選んで！","answer":"Take your pick.","tips":"Take ~~your~~ **pick**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":278,"question":"彼女はこのへんではのけ者にされてますよ。","answer":"She’s become a bit of a pariah around here.","tips":"~~She’s~~ be*come* ~~a bit of a~~ **pa*ri*ah** ~~around~~ here","level":"Hard"},{"id":279,"question":"嫉妬心が強い人は、しばしばパラノイドに見える","answer":"People with a strong tendency to be jealous often come across as paranoid.","tips":"*Peo*ple ~~with a~~ strong ten*den*cy ~~to be~~ ***jeal*ous** // *of*ten come a*cross* ~~as~~ ***pa*ranoid**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":280,"question":"私は対人トラブルを避けるために、近づかないようにしている","answer":"I won't be close to them to avoid interpersonal troubles.","tips":"~~I~~ *won’t* ~~be~~ close ~~to them~~ ~~to~~ a*void* **inter*per*sonal** *trou*bles","level":"Moderate"},{"id":281,"question":"嫉妬は、想像で自らが作り出した不安だよ。","answer":"Jealousy is just self-generated anxiety fueled by imagination, isn’t it?","tips":"***Jeal*ousy** ~~is just~~ self-*ge*nerated **anx*ie*ty** // fueled ~~by~~ **imagi*na*tion**(↘) // isn’t it(↗)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":282,"question":"事実、そこには証拠がないでしょ？","answer":"In fact, there's no actual evidence, right?","tips":"~~In~~ *fact*, // ~~there's~~ no ***ac*tual** *ev*idence(↘) // **right**(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":283,"question":"なんて言えばいいわけ？","answer":"What am I supposed to say?","tips":"**What** ~~am I~~ *sup*posed* ~~to~~ **say**(↘)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":284,"question":"そんなの全然予想してなかった","answer":"I never would've guessed","tips":"~~I~~ *nev*er ~~would’ve~~ *gue*ssed","level":"Beginner"},{"id":285,"question":"彼がそんなことをしたという証拠はどこにもないよ","answer":"There's no evidence that he did such a thing.","tips":"~~There's~~ no ***ev*idence** // ~~that he~~ **did** ~~such a~~ thing","level":"Moderate"},{"id":286,"question":"彼女が関わっていた証拠はない","answer":"There's no proof she was involved.","tips":"~~There's~~ no **proof** // ~~she was~~ in*volved*","level":"Beginner"},{"id":287,"question":"うまくいくかどうかは彼次第だね","answer":"Whether it works out or not, depends on him.","tips":"Whether ~~it~~ works out // ~~or not~~, // de*pends* ~~on~~ **him**(↘)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":288,"question":"それ今ここで言う必要あった？","answer":"Did you really hove to say that right now?","tips":"~~Did you~~ ***real*ly** ~~have to~~ say that // right now(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":289,"question":"どうしてもそれを食べる気にはなれない","answer":"I just can't bring myself to eat it.","tips":"~~I just~~ can’t bring my*self* // ~~to~~ **eat** it(↘)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":290,"question":"彼の話はなにか引っかかるところがあった","answer":"Something about what he said didn't sit right with me.","tips":"*Some*thing ~~about~~ // ~~what he~~ said // ~~didn’t~~ *si*t ***righ*t** ~~with~~ me","level":"Moderate"},{"id":291,"question":"もう何を信じればいいかわからなくなってきた","answer":"I don't even know what to believe anymore.","tips":"~~I~~ don’t *e*ven know // ~~what to~~ be*lieve* *any*more(↘)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":292,"question":"自分たち今認識あってる？","answer":"Are we on the same page right now?","tips":"~~Are we on the~~ same page right **now**(↗)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":293,"question":"自分で言うのも何だけど、私他の人より若く見えると思う。","answer":"Not to brag, but I think I look younger than most people my age.","tips":"Not ~~to~~ brag, // ~~but I~~ think ~~I~~ look ***youn*ger** // ~~than~~ most *peo*ple ~~my~~ age","level":"Extreme"},{"id":294,"question":"彼うまくやったよね？","answer":"He nailed it, didn't he?","tips":"He **nailed** ~~it~~,(↘)// didn’t ~~he~~(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":295,"question":"彼の言い方ちょっときつくなかった？","answer":"Don't you think the way he said is a bit harsh?","tips":"~~Don’t you~~ think // ~~the~~ way ~~he~~ **said** ~~is a~~ bit **harsh**(↗)","level":"Hard"},{"id":296,"question":"彼のことは受け入れたいけど、ちょっと無理","answer":"I want to accept him, but I just can't.","tips":"~~I~~ *want* ~~to~~ a*ccept* ~~him~~, // ~~but I~~ just **can’t**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":297,"question":"彼がなぜそれを続けているのかわからない","answer":"I don't even know why he continues it.","tips":"~~I~~ don’t *e*ven know // **why** ~~he~~ con*ti*nues ~~it~~(↘)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":298,"question":"結局のところ、助けてくれたのは彼だけだった。","answer":"At the end of the day, he was the only one who hellped me.","tips":"~~At the~~ end ~~of the~~ day, (↗)// ~~he was the~~ only one ~~who~~ **helped** me(↘)","level":"Hard"},{"id":299,"question":"言葉にするのは難しんだけど、、、","answer":"It's hard to put it into words, but...","tips":"~~It’s~~ hard ~~to~~ put ~~it into~~ **words**, // but...","level":"Moderate"},{"id":300,"question":"そんなに気にしないほうがいいよ","answer":"You shouldn't take it too personally.","tips":"~~You~~ shouldn’t take ~~it~~ too ***per*sonally**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":301,"question":"今のうちに言っておいたほうがいいよ","answer":"I think you should say it while you still can.","tips":"I think ~~you should~~ **say** ~~it~~ // ~~while you~~ still **can**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":302,"question":"なんだかんだ言っても、彼が唯一あなたの味方だっだよ","answer":"For all that's been said, he's the only one who's on your side.","tips":"~~For~~ all ~~that’s been~~ said, // ~~he’s the~~ only **one** // ~~who’s on your~~ **side**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":303,"question":"手遅れになる前に、日本の若者は選挙に行くべきだ","answer":"Before it's too late, young Japanese citizens must vote.","tips":"Be*fore* ~~it’s~~ too late, (↗)// young Japa*nese* citizens must **vote**","level":"Hard"},{"id":304,"question":"言いたくないんだけどさ、","answer":"I hate to say it, but","tips":"~~I~~ hate ~~to~~ say ~~it~~, // ~~but~~...","level":"Beginner"},{"id":305,"question":"誰のせいでもなく自分の責任で生きる","answer":"Live taking full responsibility for yourself—not blaming anyone else.","tips":"**Live** taking full responsi*bi*lity ~~for~~— your*self* // ~~not~~ blaming ~~anyone~~ **else**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":306,"question":"さもなくば一生その闇から出ることはできない","answer":"Otherwise, you'll stay trapped in that darkness forever.","tips":"***Oth*erwise**, ~~you’ll~~ stay *trapp*ed // **in that** ***dark*ness** for*ever*","level":"Hard"},{"id":307,"question":"悪いことに限って連続して起こるもんだよ","answer":"Bad things tend to happen all at once","tips":"Bad **things** tend ~~to~~ ***ha*ppen** all ~~at~~ once","level":"Moderate"},{"id":308,"question":"でもいつかは終わる","answer":"but eventually, they come to an end.","tips":"~~But~~ even*tual*ly, ~~they~~ come ~~to an~~ *e*nd(↘)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":309,"question":"ちょっとのみにいかない？","answer":"You up for some drinks?","tips":"~~You~~ up ~~for some~~ drinks(↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":310,"question":"世の中には2種類のタイプの男がいます。","answer":"There are two types of men in the world","tips":"~~There are~~ **two** types ~~of~~ men ~~in the~~ world","level":"Extreme"},{"id":311,"question":"片方が毎日同じご飯が食べれる人、もう一方はそれにうんざりしてしまう人。","answer":"One can eat the same meal every day, while another gets quickly fed up with it.","tips":"One ~~can~~ eat ~~the~~ same **meal** *e*very **day**, (↗)// ~~while~~ a*nother* ~~gets~~ ***quick*ly** fed up ~~with it~~(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":312,"question":"もし幸せな結婚をしたいなら、前者を探すことね。","answer":"If you want a happy marriage, find the former.","tips":"~~If you~~ *wa*nt ~~a~~ ***ha*ppy** *ma*rriage, // find ~~the~~ *for*mer","level":"Moderate"},{"id":313,"question":"元旦那が私と結婚したら退屈しないだろうといった。","answer":"My ex said that if he had married me, he wouldn’t have been bored.","tips":"~~My~~ ex said ~~that if he had~~ ***ma*rried** me, (↗)// ~~he~~ wouldn’t ~~have been~~ bored(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":314,"question":"たしかに退屈はしないかもしれなかった","answer":"True (or Indeed), he wouldn’t have been bored.","tips":"**True**, // ~~he~~ wouldn’t ~~have been~~ *bor*ed","level":"Moderate"},{"id":315,"question":"けど生命がいくつあっても足りなかったでしょう（猫の命）","answer":"But he’d probably need nine lives to get through it.","tips":"~~But he’d~~ *pro*bably need ***ni*ne** *li*ves ~~to~~ ge~t~ *throu*gh ~~it~~(↘)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":316,"question":"コーヒーでも飲んどく？","answer":"Hmm… might as well grab a coffee.","tips":"**Hmm**... // migh~~t~~ ~~as well~~ grab ~~a~~ ***co*ffee**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":317,"question":"セブにいるなら、ビーチ行っといたら？","answer":"Since you're staying in Cebu, you might as well hit the beach.","tips":"Since ~~you’re~~ *stay*ing ~~in~~ Ce*bu*, // ~~you might as well~~ hit ~~the~~ **beach**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":318,"question":"子どもを持つ女性には、おおまかに2つの道があるように見える。","answer":"Among women with children, there seem to be two main paths.","tips":"A*mong* *wo*men ~~with~~ *child*ren, (↗)// ~~there~~ seem ~~to be~~ **two** **main** paths(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":319,"question":"一方は女性であることを優先し、もう一方は母親であることを優先する。","answer":"Those who prioritize their identity as women, and those who prioritize motherhood.","tips":"~~Those~~ who *pri*oritize ~~their~~ i*den*tity ~~as~~ ***wo*men**, (↗)// ~~and~~ ~~those~~ who *pri*oritize ***mother*hood**(↘)","level":"Extreme"},{"id":320,"question":"その両方の役割を等しく果たしている人はあまり多くない。","answer":"It's not common to see both roles lived out equally.","tips":"~~It’s~~ not *com*mon ~~to~~ see **both** roles lived out *equal*ly","level":"Hard"},{"id":321,"question":"嘘を付くと私、鼻の穴が広がることに気がついた","answer":"I find myself flaring my nostrils whenever I lie.","tips":"~~I~~ *fi*nd ~~my~~self *flar*ing ~~my~~ ***nos*trils** // when*e*ver ~~I~~ lie","level":"Moderate"},{"id":322,"question":"執着はまさに人が手放すべきものです","answer":"Clinging is precisely what human must let go of.","tips":"***Cling*ing** // ~~is~~ pre*ci*sely ~~what~~ *hu*man ~~must~~ let **go** ~~of~~","level":"Moderate"},{"id":323,"question":"どんなに高い山でも、情熱と根気があれば登れない山はない。","answer":"Ain’t no mountain too high if you’ve got the grit and passion to climb it.","tips":"**Ain’t** no *moun*tain too **high** // ~~if you’ve got the~~ **grit** ~~and~~ ***pas*sion** // ~~to~~ climb ~~it~~","level":"Extreme"},{"id":324,"question":"どうせなら渋滞を避けるために早めに出発した方がいいよ。","answer":"You might as well set off early to avoid the traffic.","tips":"~~You might as well~~ set off ***ear*ly** // ~~to~~ a*void* ~~the~~ *traf*fic","level":"Hard"},{"id":325,"question":"金曜日までに私の依頼したすべてのタスクを終わらせてもらえますか？","answer":"Could you ensure that all the tasks I requested are completed by Friday, please?","tips":"~~Could you~~ en*sure* // ~~that~~ all ~~the~~ **tasks** ~~I~~ re*ques*ted // ~~are~~ com*ple*ted // ~~by~~ ***Fri*day**, (↘) // ~~please~~(↗)","level":"Hard"},{"id":326,"question":"このまま順調にいけば、締切までに提出できそうですか？","answer":"Are we on track to submit it by the deadline?","tips":"~~Are we on~~ track // ~~to~~ sub*mit* ~~it~~ // ~~by the~~ ***dead*line**(↗)","level":"Moderate"},{"id":327,"question":"なんにも期待しちゃおらんよ","answer":"I'm not expecting anything.","tips":"~~I'm~~ not **ex*pect*ing** *a*nything","level":"Beginner"},{"id":328,"question":"彼女はいつも見た目ばかり気にしている","answer":"She’s always so concerned about her appearance.","tips":"~~She’s~~ *al*ways so con*cerned* // ~~about her~~ **ap*pear*ance**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":329,"question":"なのに、自分の振る舞いがどう見られているかにはまったく無自覚よね。","answer":"Yet, she is completely oblivious to how her behavior comes across.","tips":"**Yet**, ~~she is~~ **com*plete*ly** o*bli*vious // ~~to~~ how ~~her~~ be*hav*ior comes a*cross*","level":"Hard"},{"id":330,"question":"彼はお兄ちゃんと仲が悪い。","answer":"He is on bad terms with his brother.","tips":"He ~~is on~~ bad **terms** // ~~with his~~ *bro*ther","level":"Moderate"},{"id":331,"question":"視力が悪いので近づかないと誰かわからない","answer":"My eyesight is poor, so I can't tell who someone is unless they get close.","tips":"~~My~~ *eye*sight ~~is~~ **poor**,  (↗)// ~~so I~~ **can’t** tell ~~who~~ *some*one ~~is~~ // un*less* ~~they~~ ~~get~~ close","level":"Extreme"},{"id":332,"question":"6年近くセブに住んでます。","answer":"I've been living in Cebu for nearly six years.","tips":"~~I've been~~ *liv*ing ~~in~~ **Ce*bu*** // ~~for~~ *near*ly six years","level":"Moderate"},{"id":333,"question":"この国ではロックダウンだけじゃなく、オデットも経験済みです。","answer":"I experienced not only the lockdown but also Super Typhoon Odette in this country.","tips":"~~I~~ ex*per*ienced // ~~not~~ only ~~the~~ *lock*down // ~~but~~ also ***Su*per** Ty*phoon* O*dette* // ~~in this~~ *coun*try","level":"Extreme"},{"id":334,"question":"友達数人がマニラに避難しました。","answer":"A few of my friends evacuated to Manila.","tips":"~~A~~ *few*  ~~of my~~ *friends* e*vac*uated // ~~to ~~ **Ma*ni*la**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":335,"question":"電気も水も一ヶ月以上戻らなかったから。","answer":"Because water and electricity hadn’t come back for more than a month.","tips":"Be*cause* ***wa*ter** ~~and~~ **elect*ri*city** // ~~hadn’t~~ come back // ~~for~~ ~~more than a~~ month","level":"Extreme"},{"id":336,"question":"一方私のコンドは1週間も経たずに復旧しました。","answer":"While my condo got power and water back in less than a week.","tips":"~~While my~~ *con*do ~~got~~ *pow*er ~~and~~ *wa*ter **back** // ~~in~~ ~~less than a~~ **week**","level":"Extreme"},{"id":337,"question":"だから私はずっとITパークに住み続けることを選びました。","answer":"That’s why I’ve chosen to keep living in IT Park.","tips":"That’s why ~~I’ve~~ ***cho*sen** // ~~to~~ keep *liv*ing ~~in~~ IT Park","level":"Hard"},{"id":338,"question":"あなたのことを信じるしかないわね","answer":"I have to take your word.","tips":"~~I~~ have ~~to~~ take ~~your~~ word","level":"Beginner"},{"id":339,"question":"今日は大変な一日になりそうだ","answer":"This day will be a grind.","tips":"This day ~~will be a~~ **grind**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":340,"question":"また月曜か。日常に逆戻り。","answer":"Monday again. Back at a grind.","tips":"*Mon*day a*gain*. // **Back** ~~at a~~ grind","level":"Beginner"},{"id":341,"question":"そろそろ頑張らなきゃ","answer":"Time to get back to the grind.","tips":"~~Time to~~ get back ~~to the~~ **grind**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":342,"question":"それは私だけ、それもと他の人も受け取ってないのですか？","answer":"Is it just me, or have others received theirs?","tips":"~~Is it~~ just **me**, (↗)// ~~or have~~ *oth*ers re*ceived* **theirs**","level":"Hard"},{"id":343,"question":"最初に集める必要がある書類はどれですか？","answer":"Which document needs to be collected first?","tips":"***Whi*ch** *doc*ument nee~ds~ ~~to be~~ col*lect*ed ***fir*st**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":344,"question":"一番急ぎで集めるべき書類は何ですか？","answer":"What’s the most urgent document to collect?","tips":"What’s ~~the~~ ***mo*st** *ur*gent *doc*ument // ~~to~~ col*lect*","level":"Moderate"},{"id":345,"question":"私が最初に集めるべき書類はどれですか？","answer":"Which document should I gather first?","tips":"**Which** *doc*ument ~~should I~~ *gath*er **first**","level":"Beginner"},{"id":346,"question":"集めるべき書類の中で最優先なのはどれですか？","answer":"Which document is the top priority to collect?","tips":"***Whi*ch** *doc*ument ~~is the~~ **top** pri*o*rity // ~~to~~ col*le*ct","level":"Moderate"},{"id":347,"question":"私たちが最初に手に入れるべき書類は何ですか？","answer":"What’s the first document we need to get?","tips":"What’s ~~the~~ ***fir*st** *doc*ument ~~we~~ nee~~d~~ ~~to~~ get","level":"Moderate"},{"id":348,"question":"メニュー、もう少し置いておいてもらえますか？","answer":"Could you leave the menu for a bit?","tips":"~~Could you~~ leave ~~the~~ *me*nu ~~for a~~ bit (↗)","level":"Beginner"},{"id":349,"question":"日本の水道水はきれいで飲用可能です。","answer":"The tap water in Japan is clean and drinkable.","tips":"~~The~~ ***ta*p** *wa*ter ~~in~~ Ja*pan* ~~is~~ **clean** ~~and~~ ***drink*able**","level":"Moderate"},{"id":350,"question":"日本では水道水を飲んでも安全です。","answer":"Tap water is safe to drink in Japan.","tips":"***Ta*p** *wa*ter ~~is~~ **safe** ~~to~~ drink ~~in~~ Ja*pan*","level":"Moderate"},{"id":351,"question":"世界では約50カ国で水道水が安全に飲めます。","answer":"Only about 50 countries in the world provide drinkable tap water.","tips":"*On*ly ~~about~~ ***fif*ty** *coun*tries ~~in the~~ world // pro*vide* *drink*able **tap** *wa*ter","level":"Hard"}]